Guide to the Federal Theatre Project personal papers, 1926-1989
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
Federal Theatre Project personal papers
1926-1993, bulk 1936-1939
C0227
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
15.0 linear feet (29 boxes)
This collection brings together over 90 individual donations of Federal Theatre Project material. The material in this collection consists of employment papers, correspondence, scrapbooks, newspaper and magazine clippings, photographs, playscripts, programs, fliers, and production notebooks.
Federal Theatre Project (U.S.)
Historical Information
The Federal Theatre Project was a division of the Works Progress Administration (WPA), which provided employment for large numbers of artists, writers, and performers during the Great Depression (1929-1939). The Federal Theatre Project began in 1935 and, until its end in 1939, flourished as the first and only federally sponsored and subsidized theater program in the United States. Directed by Hallie Flanagan (1880-1969), it was a way for theatrical professionals to gain employment during the Depression. Individuals worked with the Federal Theatre Project in a number of capacities, including stage managers, directors, actors and actresses, puppeteers, conductors, dancers, set and costume designers, composers, and authors.
Scope and Content
This collection brings together over 90 individual donations of Federal Theatre Project material. The material in this collection consists of employment papers, correspondence, scrapbooks, newspaper and magazine clippings, photographs, playscripts, programs, fliers, and production notebooks from people who worked in a multitude of capacities with the Federal Theatre in locations around the United States.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by last name.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Multiple donations to the Federal Theatre Project Research Center by those named in this finding aid between 1975 and the early 1990s.
Related Material
The Works Progress Administration oral histories collection, the Federal Theatre Project collection, the Federal Theatre Project photograph collection, as well as other personal papers.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Federal Theatre Project (U.S.)
Subjects:
New Deal, 1933-1939.; Performing arts.; Puppet theater.; Radio and theater; Theater--United States.
Document Types:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
Contents List
- Federal Theatre Project personal papers, 1926-1991
  - Abramson, Doris, 1936-1938 (Oversize MC 4)
    Set designs by Frederick Stover for Los Angeles productions of The Warrior's Husband, Chalk Dust, and Days Without End.
  - Abramson, Doris, circa 1930s-1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Newspaper articles from fake newspapers distributed in theaters in the 1930s - The Morning-Evening and chicago Star-Gazette. One article from The Springfield Union, November 8, 1949, "'Street Scene' inaugurated American Series at Smith".
  - Abramson, Doris, undated; 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Correspondence between Lorraine Brown and Doris Abramson with accompanying unidentified production photograph.
  - Abramson, Doris, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Correspondence between Abramson and Theodore Browne.
  - Anderson, Tommy, February - September 1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Radio scripts: The F.M.P. Negro Melody Singers, The Negro Melody Singers, Negro Art Singers, Symphony no. 5 in E minor, opus 64, page 2 from The Story of Swing.
  - Arent, Arthur, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Photocopy of It's Up to You playscript
  - Baird, Bil, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Article Puppets and Marionettes from unknown publication.
  - Barnouw, Erik, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Article Take it away, Hollywood: transcript of the memorable coast-to-coast broadcast for WPA on Monday midnight, June 26 [1939] from unkown publication.
  - Blake, Eubie, November 1937 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Photocopy of original music "Ain't We Got Love" from Swing It.
  - Blake, Eubie, November 1937 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Photocopy of original music "By the Sweat of Your Brow" from Swing It.
  - Blake, Eubie, November 1937 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Photocopy of original music "Green and Blue" from Swing It.
  - Blake, Eubie, November 1937 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Photocopy of original music "Huggin' and Muggin'" from Swing It.
  - Bolton, Harold, April 23-30, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Translation of review of Professor Mamlock in the Morning Journal; letter from an audience survey of Professor Mamlock.
  - Bolton, Rhoda Rammelkamp, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 9)
    The Dog Beneath the Skin director's copy playscript.
  - Bolton, Rhoda Rammelkamp, circa 1936-1939 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Medicine Show costume design original sketches (1 of 3),
  - Bolton, Rhoda Rammelkamp, circa 1936-1939 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Medicine Show costume design original sketches (2 of 3),
  - Bolton, Rhoda Rammelkamp, circa 1936-1939 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Medicine Show costume design original sketches (3 of 3),
  - Bolton, Rhoda Rammelkamp, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Medicine Show handwritten notes and drawings.
  - Bolton, Rhoda Rammelkamp, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Costume designs for Miles Gloriousus.
  - Bolton, Rhoda Rammelkamp, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Costume designs for One-Third of a Nation.
  - Bolton, Rhoda Rammelkamp, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    One-Third of a Nation newspaper articles, costume design notes and lists.
  - Bolton, Rhoda Rammelkamp, circa 1936-1939 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Unidentified costume designs.
  - Bromley, Robert, June 9, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    2 programs for Abu Hassan and The Princess and the Pea.
  - Bromley, Robert, circa 1931-1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Multiple articles and newspaper clippings on puppet and marionette productions.
  - Bromley, Robert, 1933-1948 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Non Federal Theatre Project play programs, many of which are marionette productions.
  - Bromley, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Scrapbook pages with articles about puppets and marionettes.
  - Bromley, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Captain Kidd playscript.
  - Burman, Harold, July 29, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Playscript and newspaper article for One-Third of a Nation Philadelphia version.
  - Burries-Meyer, Harold, 1935-1938 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Federal Theatre Project press scrapbook containing primarily newspaper and press clippings, programs, and a form letter to Harry Hopkins in regards to the firing of Elmer Rice.
  - Buttitta, Tony, July 26, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Letter to Tony Buttitta from Eva Le Gallienne with accompanying photograph of Hallie Flanagan.
  - Chavkin, Samuel, circa 1930s (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Photocopy of publicity pages for a production of Trojan Incident at St. James Theatre.
  - Cheney, Sheldon, 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Photocopies of: program notes for The Dance of Death, newspaper articles on the Federal Theatre Project, correspondence.
  - Cohen, Elizabeth Elson, circa 1935-1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Program for the marionette play Crock of Gold.
  - Cohen, Elizabeth Elson, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Newspaper clippings featuring the plays The Farmer's Wife, It Can't Happen Here, and Chalk Dust. One book review titled Theater: New York and Moscow.
  - Cohen, Gail, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Photocopies of miscellaneous newspaper clippings including a 1935 Philadelphia Inquirer article about Helen Schoeni, assistant regional director of the WPA theatrical projects and an article form a 1935 Boston Transcript about the Hedgerow Theatre.
  - Cook, Alan, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Puppet teaching materials.
  - Cook, Alan, 1930s (Box 3)
    Clown marionette donated by Alan Cook, made by Lora Pattison who taught puppetry under the WPA Recreation Project at Oneonta Grammer School, South Pasadena, california. Mrs. Pattison received her puppet training in the Pasadena WPA Recreation Project.
  - Courlander, Harold, circa 1935-1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Photocopies of correspondence, newspaper articles, play programs, and plays written by Courlander.
  - Clugston, Katherine, March 13, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Clugston, Katherine, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Unpublished manuscript by Clugston titled Very Like a Whale (1 of 4).
  - Clugston, Katherine, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Unpublished manuscript by Clugston titled Very Like a Whale (2 of 4).
  - Clugston, Katherine, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Unpublished manuscript by Clugston titled Very Like a Whale (3 of 4).
  - Clugston, Katherine, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Unpublished manuscript by Clugston titled Very Like a Whale (4 of 4).
  - Daly, Frank, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Hand drawn set design for Playboy of the Western World.
  - Danzig, Frank, circa 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Employee's identification card; notice of termination of employment.
  - Danzig, Frank, April 24, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Scrapbook page with newspaper clippings.
  - Davis, Jed H., 1952-1955 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Correspondence between Jed Davis and Hallie Flanagan and correspondence between the Library of congress and Davis on researching the Federal Theatre collection.
  - Del Bourgo, Fanya Geltman, circa 1935-1939 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    3 programs for The Dance Theatre, A Dance Program for Young Folk, A Doris Humphrey-charles Weidman Dance Program.
  - Dunn, Tom, circa 1929 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Photocopy of the play Abraham's Bosom by Paul Green.
  - Ebsen, Nancy, circa 1930s (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Photocopies of Peter Goes to the Fair playscript, newspaper reviews, program, and production notes.
  - Eldridge, Elaine, May 20, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Programs for The Dance of Death and Pinocchio. Newspaper article on broken scrapbook backing featuring The Dance of Death.
  - Elliott, Michele, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Programs for Chalk Dust, cricket on the Hearth, The Devil Passes, Rip Van Winkle, The Sun and I, Prologue to Glory, The Life of Abraham Lincoln, It can't Happen Here, Nude with Pineapple, Marionette Vaudeville, The Emperor Jones, Alice in Wonderland, Battle Hymn. Mailed flier for Squaring the circle. Newspaper clippings.
  - Elliott, Michele, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    The Witch of Guinness crag by Michele Elliott.
  - Engel, Nora (Walden), circa 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Color play announcement pamphlet featuring Prologue to Glory, Haiti, On the Rocks, and One-Third of a Nation.
  - Ewing, Kay, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Photocopies. Contents include Director's letter series 2 number 2, memorandum, Little Black Sambo script excerpt and program, Holy Night newspaper clipping and production notes, Rip Van Winkle program.
  - Farran, Don, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Playscript of Dirt a living newspaper.
  - Farran, Don, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Eloise Moore dance file. contents include newspaper clippings featuring play and dance reviews, texts used for dance productions, article chicago Dance Notes.
  - Farran, Don, 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Eloise Moore dance file. Programs.
  - Farran, Don, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    I Told Santa Claus to Bring Me You sheet music.
  - Fishel, H. L., September 18, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Playscript of It Can't Happen Here with handwritten note on title page by Sinclair Lewis.
  - Flanagan, Hallie, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    Can You Hear Their Voices? correspondence and scripts, Vassar Experimental Theatre.
  - Flanagan, Hallie, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Ladies Are Made script.
  - Flanagan, Hallie, 1930-1937 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Programs, flyers, and two photographs from the Vassar college Experimental Theatre.
  - Forbes, Leon, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    First Legion production bulletin.
  - Forbes, Leon, April 28, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Prologue to Glory research file.
  - Forbes, Leon, 1936-1939 (Oversize 16)
    Scrapbook containing photographs, newspaper clippings, and programs. Photographs include portraits (some of which are signed), production photographs, and cast group portraits. Much material relates to productions at the Alcazar Theatre in San Francisco. Shows represented include Prologue to Glory, The Sun and I, Spirochete, Power, It Can't Happen Here, and The Taming of the Shrew.
  - France, Richard (from Paul Myers), circa 1936 (Oversize MC 4)
    Oversize. Blueprint for the preliminary elevation and ground plan castle scene of Macbeth, designed by Nat Karson.
  - France, Richard (from Edna Thomas), circa 1935-1939 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Photocopies of actors notes and cues for Macbeth.
  - Friends of the Library, circa 1932-1938 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Bryn Mawr Summer School songs.
  - Galea, Manuel, 1938-1939 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Federal Theatre Project official documents transferring rights of works.
  - Galea, Manuel, circa 1935-1939 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Program for A Festival of American Dance, 12 photographs by Ralph Samuels of American Holidays dance production.
  - Galea, Manuel, January 1937 (Oversize 17, Folder 1)
    Revue of Reviews sheet music.
  - Gerwing, George, November 24, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Bird of Paradise program.
  - Gerwing, George, 1934-1938 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Correspondence, memoranda, Federal Theatre Project in San Francisco survey.
  - Gerwing, George, 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Newspaper clippings.
  - Gerwing, George, circa 1930s (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Photograph of Hallie Flanagan signed to Gerwing.
  - Gerwing, George, 1936-1938 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Publications including issues of Federal Theatre, The Prompter, Variety, and The Federal Theatre Show Parade.
  - Gerwing, George, 1937 (Oversize 18)
    Scrapbook titled "curtains up on Region of the West." contains painted costume and set designs, photographs depicting staged productions, civilian conservation corps camps, miniature theatre models. There is also one painted over photograph.
  - Gilder, Rosamund, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Photocopies of correspondence between Gilder and Hallie Flanagan.
  - Gilman, Harold and Ida, 1934-1940 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Photocopies of newspaper clippings, program material for a production of Faust, program for Page-Stone Ballet, program for Graff Ballet.
  - Glyer, Richard, 1937-1939 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Newspaper clippings featuring Spirochete, Taming of the Shrew, and Ready, Aim, Fire?. Photocopy of newspaper clipping featuring the Los Angeles Federal Theatre Project. Notice of reinstatment for terminated employees to continue on the payroll until September 30, 1939.
  - Grayson, Philip, circa 1936-1939
    Stage brace believed to be from the Federal Theatre Project.
  - Griffin, William Scott, 1930s (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Federal Theatre employment papers, birthday card, newspaper clipping.
  - Griffin, William Scott, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    King Henry the Fifth prologue, poem titled A Nightmare, exercises for speech, speech drills.
  - Griffin, William Scott, circa 1930s (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Peer Gynt script.
  - Griffin, William Scott, 1936-1945 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Photographs from oversize "The Spiral" scrapbook.
  - Griffin, William Scott, 1936-1939 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Loose material removed from "The Spiral" scrapbook. Newspaper clippings, invitation to "The Mask and the Face," program for "Smilin' Through."
  - Griffin, William Scott, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Scrapbook on the Miami Federal Players (1 of 2). Newspaper clippings and programs.
  - Griffin, William Scott, 1936-1938 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Scrapbook on the Miami Federal Players (2 of 2). Newspaper clippings and programs about the Miami Federal Players, also programs for cloyd Head's Miami Players, Shawn and his men dancers, Temple Theatre, and a script titled "Blocks" by Molly Day Thatcher.
  - Griffin, William Scott, 1936-1938 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    Scrapbook with a brown cover (1 of 2). Portrait and production photographs include Dorothea Thomas Lynch, and Scott Griffin, programs, newspaper and magazine clippings, some pertaining to Molka Reich and marionettes.
  - Griffin, William Scott, 1934-1936 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    Scrapbook with a brown cover (2 of 2). Programs, newspaper clippings relating to the Miami Federal Theatre. Photographs of marionette productions, material relating to Molka Reich.
  - Griffin, William Scott, 1934-1937 (Oversize 19)
    Brown scrapbook covers; "The Spiral" scrapbook which contains Federal Theatre Project newspaper clippings, telegrams, and programs related to the Miami Federal Players. There is also a program for the Erlanger Theatre in Atlanta, Georgia for a production of The Barretts of Wimpole Street.
  - Gupta, Robin, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Copies of 3 articles from the Saturday Evening Post about the Federal Theatre Project.
  - Hagan, R. Lyle, 1931-1942 (Oversize 20)
    Scrapbook with writing inside the front cover: "Federal Theatre of the Midwest year 1939. Prologue to Glory production - 75 performances. R. Lyle Hagan as 'Abe' Lincoln." Includes newspaper and magazine clippings including a newspaper from 1931 and a New Yorker from 1942, programs, and photographs. The photographs include signed headshots, actors at work, and outside of work.
  - Harms, carl, 1934-1990s (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Contains: one photograph of a muppet created by Bil Bairds walking in a parade from the 1990s; photographs from productions at the Great Northern Theatre in July 1938 that include Kurt Graff, Ruth Page, Carl Harms and others; programs; magazine articles; notice of assignment for Carl Harms.
  - Harms, Carl, 1935-1991 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Harris, Julian, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Programs for Atlanta productions of The Drunkard, Altars of Steel, Mary the Third, The Torch Bearers, Excursion, Boy Meets Girl, Around the corner, The Devil's Disciple, By Candlelight.
  - Harris, Julian, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Flyers and newspaper clippings about Federal Theatre productions in Atlanta, program for Faust, photocopy of photograph of Julian Harris, documents include a proposed working agreement between Atlanta Theatre Guild and the Atlanta Federal Theatre, and notice of termination of employment.
  - Hatch, James V., January 1938 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Miniature theatre models constructed by Research Bureau Regional Service Department Federal Theater Project Region of the West booklet.
  - Haufrecht, Herbert, 1938-1984 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    The Story of Ferdinand and String Fever program, photocopies of newspaper clippings on The Story of Ferdinand and String Fever performances from the 1940s to the 1980s.
  - Hauser, Ethel Aaron, January 1937 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Power playscript.
  - Hauser, Ethel Aaron, January 17, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    One-Third of a Nation living newspaper program.
  - Hauser, Ethel Aaron, 1936-1938 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Program for The Dance of Death; Murder in the Federal Theatre! Published by the Federal Theatre Project Supervisors' council; Promotional material for Injunction Granted! and One-Third of a Nation; Memorandum from T. A. Mauntz to Ethel Aaron.
  - Hermanson, Hjalmar, 1936 (Oversize 21)
    Scenic and set designs, by Hjalmar Hermanson for the plays Ethiopia, Triple-A Plowed Under, and 1935. Designs are mounted onto storyboards that measure 15 inches high by 20 inches wide. There are four for Ethiopia, Five for Triple-A Plowed Under, and five for 1935.
  - Hermanson, Hjalmar, 1936 (Oversize 22, Folder 1)
    Triple-A Plowed Under photographs.
  - Hermanson, Hjalmar, 1936 (Oversize 22, Folder 2)
    1935 photographs.
  - King, Woody (from Mrs. Rudolph Fisher), 1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    The Conjure Man Dies playscript.
  - King, Woody (from Mrs. Rudolph Fisher), 1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - King, Woody (from Mrs. Rudolph Fisher), 1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Koch, Howard, May 16, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Program for The Lonely Man.
  - Krasney, Myron, 1930s-1940s (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Photographs of puppet performance in Philadelphia as well as performances of One-Third of a Nation and the Federal Theatre Dance Project.
  - Lane, Esther Porter, 1937-1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Scrapbook pages removed from scrapbook containing mostly newspaper clippings and programs relating to Seattle productions.
  - Lane, Esther Porter, circa 1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Programs, photographs, artwork from Seattle Federal Theatre Project productions including Is Zat So, Brer Rabbit, Black Empire, Flight, One-Third of a Nation, Mother Goose.
  - Lane, Esther Porter, 1936-1940 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Programs for The Emperor's New clothes, Native Ground, Seattle children's Theatre, Medicine Show, Love in Humble Life, Julius caesar, The Path of Flowers, Sweet Land, The Straw, The Show-Off, The Pursuit of Happiness, Professor Mamlock, Haiti, The Mikado.
  - Lane, Esther Porter, 1935-1938 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Contains: Employee identification card, telegrams, letters regarding employment, recommendation letters; flyers, announcements, newspaper clippings about Seattle productions.
  - Lane, Esther Porter, circa 1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Two photographs possibly of Injunction Granted.
  - Lane, Esther Porter, circa 1930s (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Script for Mother Goose and Us (children's play).
  - Larsen, Agnete Johansen, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Photocopies of newspaper clippings and a letter.
  - Laub, Lili Mann, 1934-1947 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Photocopies of newspaper clippings and programs.
  - Lavery, Emmet, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Photocopy of unpublished material by Lavery that was planned as a chapter in The Flexible Stage. A copy of The Flexible Stage is found in the Federal Theatre Project collection box 154 folders 8 and 9.
  - Lehac, Ned, circa 1930s (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Photocopy of script for Papa's Got a Job; script for Pop's a cop in Jersey city; photocopy of opening scene of Sing For Your Supper.
  - Lehac, Ned, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Sing For Your Supper production notebook.
  - Lehac, Ned, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    Sing For Your Supper sheet music - Imagine My Finding You Here.
  - Lehac, Ned, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Sing For Your Supper sheet music - Papa's Got a Job.
  - Leve, Samuel, June 2, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Cherokee Nights set sketches for performance at the Provincetown Playhouse.
  - Leve, Samuel, 1936 (Oversize 28)
    Cherokee Nights set model. It is made out of paper, wood, and clay and measures approximately 12 inches by 9 1/5 inches by 11 1/2 inches. The set consists of a box painted black with the top and one side exposed. There are two pieces of string that criss cross the top part of the box. The set itself has four moveable parts, two of which look like rock piles, one looks like a doorway that comes out of a rock pile, and the last piece is a wooden fence. The background consists of three pieces of paper that are painted blue.
  - Leve, Samuel, October 6, 1944 (Oversize 29)
    Hand in Glove set model. Made out of wood and paper. The model consists of two main parts that swivel 360 degrees to provide two different sets. One is of the back of a house, the other is inside the house. The walls of the house has pencil drawings on it. The model measures 13.5 inches long by 8 inches high by 10 1/4 inches wide. Two stamps are present on the front of the model. Both are for the United Scenic Artists Local 829. Handwritten on the front is "For Arthur Edison, Hand in Glove, by c.K. Freeman & G. Savory Scale 1/4" = 1', 10-6-44, S. Leve."
  - Leve, Samuel, circa 1936-1939 (Oversize 26)
    Set model for unknown production, approximately 7 1/2 inches wide and 4 1/4 inches high. Made out of wood, paper, and clay, the set features a hill with trees and two walls with part of a grass hut roof. There are pencil sketches on the walls of the hut.
  - Leve, Samuel, 1951 (Oversize 27)